Robert BrieseAgile Coach & Consultant



+49 163 730 1346 robert.briese@briese-ssc.com www.briese-ssc.com

Summary

Robert Briese is a Certified ScrumMaster® (CSM) and Certified Scrum Product Owner® (CSPO) as well as a SAP Certified NetWeaver Consultant and former SAP Mentor in the area of Portal and Knowledge Management & Collaboration. He has been working as technical consultant and project manager since 2002, carrying over 30 different portal and knowlege management implementations worldwide and is now an expert in agile methods like Scrum and Kanban.

Among others, he was responsible for the design and implementation of the knowledge management platform in the SAP intranet portal (Employee Network) and supported the rollout of the HR Portal at BP International PLC into ten countries. In the past four years, Robert has acted as Consultant and Trainer for Product Owners and ScrumMasters at different companies. As Product Owner he was responsible for the design and implementation of SAP's biggest web site http://help.sap.com with over 10 millions pages and 500,000 hits per day, as well as the SAP internal address book replacement. In his last assignment he helped the Vaillant Group transition from waterfall project management to agile frameworks based on Scrum and Kanban that support project and maintenance work in mixed teams of developers, consultants and project managers.

Robert is ranked among the all-time top contributors to the SAP Community Network (SCN) discussion forums "Portal" and "Knowledge Management," and was honored for four consecutive years as a top contributor by the SAP board committee. Furthermore, from 2007-2011, he was a SAP Mentor and is now a SAP Mentor alumni. The SAP Mentor program is a highly selective program recognizing those individuals making an outstanding contribution to the SAP ecosystem (http://sapmentors.sap.com).

Personal Information

Born 15.05.1976 Nationality German

Languages

English Fluent

French Good Command

German Mother Tongue

Romanian Mother Tongue

Spanish Extended Knowledge

Education

1996-10 - 2002-10 Business Information Technology University of Applied Sciences - Paderborn

Certifications

Technology Consultant SAP NetWeaver - Enterprise Portal & Knowledge Management SAP Consultant Certification

Managing Projects – Project Management Core Curriculum PMI Certification

Certified ScrumMaster® Scrum Alliance Certification

Certified Scrum Product Owner® Scrum Alliance Certification

Employment History

2007-05 – Present Briese System Solution Consulting (self-employed)

2006-10 - 2007-04 Capgemini Deutschland GmbH

2003-10 - 2006-09 btexx business technologies GmbH

2002-10 - 2003-09 University of Paderborn

2002-01 - 2002-08 KPMG Consulting AG

1999-05 - 2001-12 University of Paderborn

Engagements

2006-10 - 2006-12

2014-07 - 2014-12	Vaillant Group Business Services GmbH
	ScrumMaster and agile coach for two teams transitioning from waterfall project management to an agile framework. Introducing Scrum and Kanban and developing a model to support project and maintenance work in a mixed team of developers and project managers
2010-12 - 2014-05	SAP AG
	Product Owner for SAP's biggest documentation site - SAP Help Portal (http://help.sap.com)
	Product Owner for SAP's address book replacement, an internal expert finding tool (People@SAP)
	Project Manager for SAP's customer influence site (influence.sap.com)
	Consultant and Scrum coach for various teams at SAP IT
2009-08 - 2010-12	BP International PLC
	Implementation of Performance Management based on SAP ECC EHP4 and SAP NetWeaver Portal EHP1
2009-05 - 2009-07	BP International PLC
	Go-Live support for BPpeople (HR) portal based on SAP NetWeaver Portal 7.0
2009-03 - 2009-04	Bausparkasse Schwäbisch Hall AG
	Consulting / Training of SAP Basis team on SAP NetWeaver Portal 7.0 technology topics
2008-01 - 2008-10	SAP Americas Inc.
	Project lead of the ECM (Enterprise Content Management) @ SAP project – Document & Asset Management workstream based on SAP NetWeaver Portal 7.0
2007-01 – 2007-12	SAP AG
	Solution Manager / Technical project lead for the implementation of the collaboration platform of the SAP Business ByDesign Business Center (www.sme.sap.com) based on SAP NetWeaver Portal 7.0
2006-12	Syngenta International AG
	Conceptual design and implementation of the employee portal based on SAP NetWeaver Portal 7.0 and SAP CRM 5.0

HSH Nordbank

Blueprint design for the integration of diverse applications into the

employee portal based on SAP NetWeaver Portal 7.0

2006-06 - 2006-09 Hilti Corporation

Blueprint design of Hilti employee portal based on SAP NetWeaver Portal

NetWeaver 7.0

2006-05 **ZF Friedrichshafen**

Blueprint workshop for analyzing the implementation of the knowledge

portal based on XML forms and SAP Enterprise Portal 6.0

2006-03 Altana AG

Conceptual design and implementation of a comprehensive KM migration -

 $\ensuremath{\mathsf{EP}}\xspace$ 6.0 SP2 to NW'04, Going-Live Support of the Altana employee portal

based on SAP Enterprise Portal NetWeaver 2004

2006-03 **Hugo Boss AG**

Hands-On Workshop and enhancement implementations in the Knowledge

Management platform of the Hugo Boss Retail Portal based on SAP

NetWeaver Portal 2004

2006-02 - 2006-09 **Brose Automotive**

Project lead and technical coach in Knowledge Management for the Brose

intranet portal based on SAP NetWeaver Portal 2004

2006-02 - 2006-09 data process GmbH

Technical coach on portal technology activities for the K+S internal portal

based on SAP NetWeaver Portal 2004

2006-02 Sasol Germany GmbH

Troubleshooting of the Sasol internal portal based on SAP Enterprise Portal

6.0

2006-02 - 2006-04 **MEWA**

Implementation of a high availability portal landscape based on SAP

NetWeaver Portal 2004 with subsequent migration of existing content

2006-01 **ZF** Friedrichshafen

Integration of Windows File Servers into the SAP KM Platform using SSO $\,$

and WebDAV Repository Manager based on SAP Enterprise Portal 6.0

2005-10 - 2005-11 SAP AG

Conceptual design, implementation and go-live support of the SAP

Corporate Portal subproject "Office of the CEO" based on SAP NetWeaver

Portal 2004

2005-12 **Hugo Boss AG**

Go-Live Support of the Hugo Boss Retail Portal based on SAP NetWeaver

Portal	2004

2005-05 - 2005-10	SAP AG
	Technical lead for the "KM platform" of the SAP Corporate Portal project (New SAP employee Portal) based on SAP NetWeaver Portal 2004
2005-01 - 2005-12	SAP AG
	Conceptual design, implementation and go-live support of the SAP Corporate Portal subproject "Knowledge Base for Shared Service Center (SSC)" based on SAP NetWeaver Portal 2004
2005-01	Rasselstein Hoesch GmbH
	Implementation and go-live support of the Rasselstein employee portal based on SAP NetWeaver Portal 2004
2004-12	REWE-Informations-Systeme GmbH
	Implementation of a development portal based on SAP NetWeaver Portal 2004
2004-11 - 2004-12	Dr. August Oetker Nahrungsmittel KG
	Conceptual design, implementation and go-live support of the Dr. Oetker Intranet Portal projects based on SAP Enterprise Portal 6.0 SP2
2004-08 - 2004-11	ZF Friedrichshafen
	Conceptual design, implementation and go-live support of the ZF portal project "IT-Communication Platform" based on SAP Enterprise Portal 6.0
2004-08 - 2004-10	Rasselstein Hoesch GmbH
	Conceptual design, implementation and go-live support of the Rasselstein employee portal project based on mySAP Enterprise Portal 6.0
2004-06	Wacker Chemie
	Knowledge Management Feasibility Study: "Implementation of a portal prototype environment based on SAP Enterprise Portal 6.0"
2004-05	Volkswagen AG
	Implementation of a development portal based on SAP Enterprise Portal 6.0 - HP ProLiant Server ML570 configuration
2004-04	Wacker Chemie
	Implementation of a new portal layout in SAP Enterprise Portal 6.0
2004-03	RAG INFORMATIK GmbH

Consulting / Training of Customer Support employees in SAP Enterprise $\,$

Portal 6.0 Technology

2004-02	Henkel KgaA
	Implementation of a development portal based on SAP Enterprise Portal 6.0
2004-01 - 2004-12	ZF Friedrichshafen
	Conceptual design, implementation and go-live support of the ZF employee portal based on SAP Enterprise Portal 6.0
2004-01	LHI Leasing GmbH
	Creation of business blueprint for the integration of various applications into the SAP Enterprise Portal 6.0